ARUN VISHWAKARMA (1) Featured

Application Developer @Oracle, seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software **Development, Application Development**

Hands on experience in Core Java, Debugging, Eclipse, Python, Spring MVC, Git, Jenkin,

AGILE, WaterFall, JUnit, JavaScript, Oracle SQL, Maven



Current Designation: Application Developer Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Oracle Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Gurgaon, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Development, Requirement Gathering, Core Java, Debugging, Eclipse, Python, Spring MVC, Git, Jenkin, AGILE, WaterFall, JUnit, Maven, Oracle SQL, JDeveloper, JSP,

Servlets, JDBC,

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Summary

Currently working in Oracle with 3+ years of experience in Development, Design and Testing of Java based Applications using Java/J2EE technologies.

Experience in SDLC(Software Development Life Cycle) that includes Analysis, Design, Coding, Testing and Implementation and Maintenance with methodologies like Waterfall and Agile.

Excellent experience on Core Java mechanisms like Multithreading, Collections and Exception Handling

Good Hands on experience with Spring Framework

Experience in Analyzing User Stories and functional requirements.

Knowledge of JDeveloper and Maven tool for the development of Java projects.

Hands on experience in using Tomcat Server and WebLogic server.

Experience in creating testcases using Junit.

Experience in Oracle database.

Strong Debugging and Troubleshooting skills.

Consistently received appreciation from Manager

Work Experience

Oracle as Application Developer

May 2019 to Till Date

Description: Oracle eAM is part of Oracle E-Business Suite, which deals with managing assets of the asset intensive organizations. Asset could be Fixed or Rebuildable. The key modules of application are as follows:

Creating Work Order on asset

Performing inter-org transfer on assets Issuing items from stores to the WO

Environment: Operating System

Linux

Technical Stack

Oracle Application Framework, Java, J2EE, SQL, PL/SQL

Tools

Jdeveloper, Eclipse, SQL Builder

My Role:

Oracle EBS 12.2.10 enhancements for eAM module.

Involved in coding, unit testing and code reviews on regular basis

Understanding customer issues and trying to come up with the solutions at the earliest.

Infosys Ltd as Systems Engineer

Oct 2017 to May 2019

Duration: October 2017 - May 2019

Description: Ricoh is a Japanese multi-national imaging and electronics company and produces electronic products,

primarily cameras and office equipment such as printers, photocopiers and fax machines

Environment: Operating System

Linux

Technical Stack

Java, J2EE, SQL, PL/SQL

Tools

Eclipse, SQL Builder

My Role:

Analysis of user's requirements, design and develop java base applications.

Integrating the module with other modules.

Coordinating with other programmers in the team to ensure that all the modules complement each other well.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from GLA Institute of technology and management, Mathura in 2017

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Foundations Associate

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Java, Python, PL/SQL, Junit, Git	
Servlet, JSP, JDBC, Spring BOOT	
Oracle EBS, JavaScript, Maven	
Tomcat, WebLogic, Oracle, Linux	
Eclipse, NetBeans, PyCharm	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time